First, open Marvelous Designer and find a VR male and double-click to enter the working area in the virtual model file house in the window of the library.
To show directly, switch the display type of the model to black and white surface.
Select the rectangle tool in the drop-down menu on the menu bar.
First, create a rectangle with a length of 20x200.
Click on the positioning tool in the upper right corner of the location.
Then click on the virtual model.
You can quickly place it near the virtual model.
To compare, the width is too narrow, so open this panel along the side.
To quickly adjust the line, delete the excess straight lines.
The comparison is still a bit narrow, drag the side to widen the panel.
In the process of moving the line,
press the Shift key to move along the reference line.
Press the right mouse button to enter the specific number.
Use the edit texture tool to check the gold tail of the panel.
Because we want to shrink the panel horizontally,
so we have to shrink it in the direction of the arrowhead,
which is to reduce the tail shrink.
Because we are going to use the fixer tool later,
the fixer is also fixed at the top of the grid,
so we have to reduce the particle diameter before adding the fixer.
Open the simulation.
The panel will be hung on the hand.
To make it easier to observe the effect,
change the fabric color first.
After rotating the view, you can see that
the band should be a fabric that fits the human body,
but now there is some distance between the human body.
Reducing the conflict thickness can reduce the air thickness around the panel.
The conflict thickness is a property that produces instability in order to prevent the grid from being too close to the top.
After opening the simulation, you can see that the panel is closer to the human body.
At this time, there is still a certain distance between the panel and the human body,
because there is also an air thickness around the model,
which is called the surface diameter.
After selecting a part of the model,
you can modify the surface diameter of the entire model.
After opening the simulation, you can see that the fabric is completely attached to the human body.
Because we want to add a fixed needle at both ends,
and adjust the band through them,
we have to keep the two ends of the line as straight as possible.
So we have to harden the panel,
so that the panel can not be bent easily,
and the two ends will not be deformed easily.
After selecting the fixed needle tool,
you can add a fixed needle along one side of the panel line to the top of the grid.
You can add a fixed needle along one side of the panel line to the top of the grid.
Do not bend the position of the double needle again.
If you want to delete the fixed needle,
select the fixed needle and press Delete.
On the other side, continue to add the fixed needle.
Open the simulation and let the panel naturally drop.
The first grid is often relatively large and relatively small.
Therefore, although the particle diameter has been reduced,
it is still not as fine as the first grid.
We can try to reduce the particle diameter to 8 and simulate.
In order to prevent the transformation of the grid from re-placing,
we need to delete the fixed needle and repeat it.
When the cloth pin gets closer to your finger,
you will see some bulge.
You can reduce the particle diameter to 5.
Continue to repeat theנ
病化板片 and increase the fiction needle.
Repeat the hardening plate and add a fixed needle.
After removing the hardening, open the simulation, so that the fabric can naturally fall
and hang on the hand.
Then you can select the middle position of the fixed needle and click on the position as a
standard.
By rotating and moving the fixed needle, the fixed needle is close to the hand position.
If there is such a pull effect in the video, please rotate and move the fixed needle so that
the fabric can be attached to the hand as smoothly as possible.
After changing the angle, confirm that the fixed needle is close to the hand, select the
fixed to the virtual model function in the menu in the right-click, and then the fixed
needle will be fixed to the virtual model grid and will not move.
Open the simulation again at a point where the movement of the 2D window is not fixed.
Because this line is fixed in the 3D window, the 3D window will not move.
The 3D window will not move.
Since the 3D window is fixed, the 3D window will not move.
If the 3D window is fixed, the 3D window will not move.
On the other hand, the 3D window will not turn.
Now let's look at the calculation of the 3D window.
In the 3D window, the 3D window is attracted as you move it and turn it.
The 3D window is closed, and the fixed needle will be fixed, so the fabric will be
hammered in the middle.
We can continue to move and rotate the fixed needle to develop the fiber.
After that, there is the repeat operation.
During the motion of the fixed needle, please pay attention to the board.
Do not stretch it too much.
Especially when there is a pleck in the direction of movement.
It is often already a seriously stretched deformation.
Next is the operation before repetition.
Also pay attention to the switching that takes place at the stand.
We will use the hand strap to make it easier for us to wrap it around.
Pull the board by hand so that the board can be evenly attached to the palm of your hand.
Then you can wrap the board according to your needs.
Now we will use the strap to hold the board on the palm of our hand.
The palm of the hand is not used to hold the board.
Therefore, it is better for us to use the strap on the palm of the hand instead of on the palm of the palm of the palm.
As mentioned before,
we will do the same for the same part,
In the process of fixing the needle, you must remember to rotate the fixing needle occasionally, so that the board can be smoothly pasted on the palm.
After multi-layer intersection and entanglement, the board may slide together, affecting the simulation effect.
After increasing friction, it can prevent the fabric from sliding together, and it can produce a better fold effect.
When the friction coefficient is relatively low, the fabric will slide, and when we drag the board to entangle, it is easy to pile up to one position.
By entangling the fabric, the fixing needle is hidden in the end point of the model.
It is also a repeat of the previous operation. Remember to only increase the length of the fabric by moving the entire line of the fixed needle.
If you want the fabric to stick together, you can use a sewing needle to sew the two points together.
Select the sewing needle tool, click on the two fabrics, and you're done.
The sewing needle tool does not lower the totalано into the entire area of the piece.
You can approach other fabrics little by little, and through the fixed needle, the end material of the band is placed into the part that is already entangled.
Stop the simulation, hide the virtual model, and fix the fixed pin to the virtual model.
Then drag and drop, cover the end point.
Remove the fixed pin and add it again, or remove the fixed pin from the model to adjust the position of the band again.
After setting it up, re-attach it to the virtual model.
Then we are going to start making the details of the band fold.
In the previous operation, our fabric has always been shrinked, so it is narrower than the actual fabric.
Add a fixed pin and double-click to the top of the grid on both sides to fix the position of the fabric.
Then increase the reduced shrink to 90,
so that due to the difference between the two sides,
the material in the middle will change a lot.
This will form the fold.
Increase the reduced shrink to 100.
There may be too many folds.
You can choose a number according to your needs.
I chose 85 here.
If you want to have a thinner fold,
you can change the particle diameter to 3.
Because the size of this panel is not very large.
After simulation, you can see that the fold becomes more detailed.
But because there is no fixed pin on the newly added grid,
it will extend outward.
There is a problem with the protrusion on the side of the panel.
So double-click to control the grid.
Do a short simulation.
This can ensure that the fold will not return to the original shape because of the long simulation.
The pattern will maintain the current fold effect,
and can participate in the simulation.
In the simulation process,
if there is a conflict or instability due to the shape optimization,
you can use the multiple shape optimization function instead.
First cancel the shape optimization of the panel.
In the drop-down menu of the fixed pin,
select the grid, brush, tool,
click and drag the mouse on the band on the back of the hand
to select the shape optimization area.
Then select the shape optimization in the menu on the right-hand side
to perform partial shape optimization.
In this way, the unstable part on the back
can be simulated and stabilized.
And because the fold of the palm part is self-formed,
there is no problem without using the partial shape optimization function.
This video is over.
See you in the next video.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community